

Mario Dcunha is a self-driven designer, experienced engineer, traveler, and singer, with a good sense of humor. Pursuing a career in his passion for user experience design, through an overall career of seven years. Striving to influence, inspire and lead change at the workplace, to the business, and in society.

mariodcunha.com

mario.dcn@gmail.com 631 746 6451

EXPERIENCE

PRODUCT DESIGN INTERN. INTUIT

May 2018 - Aug 2018 | Plano, Texas, USA

Worked on Document management for accountants - to help generate faster tax returns and the One Intuit Accountant project - to design a seamless experience between Intuit's accounting and tax products.

- Conducted 15+ user interviews with early lo-fi a/b testing and usability tests along with the chief user researcher.
- Drew insights into users' pain, aligned them to business goals and iterated with lo-fi mocks before deliberating on shipping decisions.
- Researched current product experiences, interviewed stakeholders from across Intuit and used storyboarding and journey-mapping frameworks to gather empathy for users.
- Mapped transitions from current to ideal product states that would reduce customer call and training costs, generate faster account setups and drive the 'One Intuit' brand identity.
- Also participated in Service Blueprinting, rapid prototyping and doodled visual maps to empower team brainstorming.

SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT, AKAMAI

Mar 2013 - Jun 2017 | Bangalore, India

Analyzed websites and developed customized proof of concepts to justify Akamai's product value and improve end-user experience. Customers included sales and engineering teams of mainly Fortune 500 companies from across the globe.

- Served as subject-matter-expert for two of Akamai's products.
- Re-designed the new-hire training for Akamai sales teams, globally.
- Trained sales teams from across USA, Costa-Rica, Japan and Bangalore in web performance and front-end optimization.
- Mentored and groomed four new hires individually, into dependable resources within six months.
- Designed infographics to assist Akamai product marketing teams.

SYSTEMS ENGINEER, INFOSYS

Nov 2010 - Dec 2012 I Chennai, India

Worked as a FinTech engineer on UI development, automation testing and back-end debugging.

EDUCATION

TEACHING ASSISTANT, THE NEW SCHOOL

Oct 2017 to date I New York City, USA

Tutoring students majoring in UX Design and Data Visualization on creative coding with JavaScript. Worked as an instructional designer to improve online courses for students and faculty of various age groups.

M.F.A. DESIGN AND TECHNOLOGY

Aug 2017 - May 2019 | New York City, USA Parsons School of Design | CGPA 3.93/4.0

B.E. COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Aug 2006 – May 2010 | Nitte, India NMAM Institute of Technology | GPA 3.6/4.0

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 'Zagrut' reached the Top 12 finalists from over 100 projects, at the PILOT Innovation Challenge, National Association of Broadcasters, USA, Nov 2018.
- Presented 'Zagrut' at NYC Media Lab Summit, Sep 2018.
- ▶ Won three Spotlight awards for outstanding contribution towards product benchmarking, client satisfaction and intra-team initiatives, Akamai, Bangalore, 2015.
- Reached the Top 30 from 475 ideas at the Global Idea Summit, 'Akamai Wizards', 2014.
- Secured first rank in the Design Thinking evaluation by 'The UX Academy', Infosys, 2012, from 300+ participants across Infosys, India, that recognised potential designers.
- Created MadeByMAD.design personal graphic design label for tees and other merchandise.

SKILLS

- Sketch, Invision, Adobe Creative Suite
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript: p5, d3, node.js, socket.io
- OO Programming: Java, C#
- Unity, 2D, 3D, VR